for fuel they raised the price by 3 rubles And that’s it Well,
на топливо на 3 рубля подняли цену И всё
yes, bread is the same as it was 45 so it is
да Ну да хлеб как был 45 так он есть
45 or 39 what kind of
45 или 39 какой там
loaf cars are there cars also went up by 3 rubles
батон автомобили тоже на 3 руб
cars that European ones
поднялись автомобили что европейские
went to European cars in
ушли на европейские автомобили в
principle well yes they raised prices a little for me It’s
принципе ну да чуть подняли цены у меня
just a European car  from RUB or
Европейский просто автомобиль с руб или
for 5 RUB
на 5 руб
Hello Hello I am from the city of
Здравствуйте Привет Я из города
Khmelnitsky You
Хмельницкий Вы
[music] are
[музыка]
from Krasnodar about the World Cup, you talk
откуда Краснодара о ЧМ общаетесь
here about everything, probably like you  how do
тут обо всём наверно как у вас люди как
people in Krasnodar feel about the fact that
люди в Краснодаре относятся к тому что
the war has
война так долго
been going on for so long? Yes, in principle, the question is nano for all of
идёт Да в принципе вопрос нано ко всей
Russia, not only
России не только
Krasnodar, well, how do you live in Krasnodar? How do
Краснодар ну как вот вы же в Краснодаре
you people, your friends there,
живёте Как у вас люди ваши знакомые там
neighbors, how do
соседи как
they feel normally, they are not tired of the
они нормально относятся не устали от
war Yes  no,
войны Да нет не
we’re not tired, it’s cool, we somehow don’t
устали прикольно мы как-то тут не
feel here, it’s just that there’s some kind of war,
ощущаем просто что какая-то война
we’re not being mobilized here, it’s like they’re being shoved
есть нас тут не мобилизуют как бы суют
anywhere. Where do you get the floor, where do you get it?
Никуда А откуда у вас пол откуда у вас
The army is being replenished, in the sense that contract soldiers go on their own
армия в смысле контрактники идут сами
Pony boys are not forcing me, I understand Well,
пацаны Поня не заставляют я понял Да ну
no one is forcing me, well, I read in the
не заставляют никто ну я я читал в
news that the police are catching someone there and they
новостях что там полиция кого ловит да
very persistently offer to sign a
очень настойчиво предлагает подписать
contract. Well, who told you that,
контракт Да ну это кто вам это сказал
your prices haven’t gone up either. I
цены у вас тоже не поднялись Я так
understand the prices for what, let’s do this For  2 and a
понимаю цены на что давайте так За 2 с
half years of war, what
поло года войны что у вас в худшую
has changed for the worse in
сторону изменилось в
Russia? For fuel, they raised prices by 3 rubles
России на топливо на 3 руб подняли цены
and that’s
и всё
it. Well, bread was the same as it was 45, so it is
да Ну да хлеб как был 45 так он есть
45 or 39, what kind of
45 или 39 какой там
loaf are cars? Cars also went up by 3 rubles.
батон автомобили тоже на 3 руб
that the Europeans
поднялись автомобили что европейские
have gone to European cars, in
ушли на европейские автомобили в
principle, well, yes, they raised the prices of a
принципе ну да ть подняли цены
European car by how much
Европейский просто автомобиль на сколько
by 3 rubles or 5
на 3 руб или на 5
rubles, well, every spare part if you
руб ну каждая запчасть если там по
take the chassis there, you probably went up by two,
ходовки брать ты на две наверно
yes How
поднялась да Со
much? Well, let’s say from de to 11 I’m like this  from
скольки Ну допустим с де на 11 я вот так
about 9 to 11 - this is more than a 20%
примерно с 9 на 11 - это больше 20%
increase, well, probably, I didn’t count. I don’t
прирост ну наверное да я же не считал Не
know, I understand, but everything else has not
знаю понял а остальное всё Не
risen in price, but what are we, what are we
подорожало ну а что мы мы мы же что тут
buying here? Where  where do you buy bread for 45 rubles
покупаем Где где вы хлеб по 45 руб
and what kind of
покупаете и какой
bread is it the highest grade, good bread
хлеб это высшего сорта хороший хлеб
Wheaten with the first Well, the highest grade And
Пшеничный с первой Ну высшего сорта А
where where can you see on what website
где где можно посмотреть на каком сайте
you can see the price of such bread Well
можно посмотреть цену такого хлеба Ну
look at the Krasnovsky region chain of
посмотрите красновский край сеть
stores Gourmand Now look
магазинов Гурман Сейчас
this is the village Vyselki village this is
посмо это станица станица Выселки этот
where I am  I
где я
live now, let’s see,
живу сейчас посмотрим
I’m really interested. Maybe it’s
так мне же интересно действительно Может
45 rubles. Bread So 4539 loaf, in my opinion,
там 45 руб Хлеб Так 4539 батон по-моему
costs 39, in my opinion Yes, I recently bought it, I
39 стоит по-моему Да недавно покупал я
just buy cigarettes in general
просто всё в общем покупаю сигареты
they’re expensive,
дорого стоят
so look, it’s
вот значит смотри
opened in Google, it means the Kuban
открыл в Гугле значит Кубанский
Agricultural
Сельскохозяйственный
Information and Consultation Center, so
информационно-консультационный центр так
they have a PDF, here are the prices for bread, flour and cereals
у них ПДФ вот цены на хлеб муку и крупы
in the Krasnodar Territory as of
в Краснодарском крае по состоянию на
10.09 of the year, that is, on September 10 of the
10.09 че года то есть на 10 ээ сентября
fourth year, come on, rye rye bread
д четвёртого года Да ну хлеб ржаной
rye-wheat
ржаной ржано-пшеничный
uh 93 rub 51
ээ 93 руб 51
kopecks so uh bread and bakery products
коп так э хлеб и хлебобулочные изделия
from  premium wheat flour 100 rubles
из пшеничной муки высшего сорта 100 руб
83 kopecks
83 коп
Why are you driving me away now I have the bread I
Вы что гоните я те сейчас у меня Хлеб
think there are even tags I’ll
по-моему есть даже бирки я те сечас
show you now let’s show something for the bread
покажи давай покажи что-то за хлеб
interesting pockets the bread is good les ses
интересно карманы хлеб хороший ле сес
this is the kind of bread I just
вот такой хлеб просто у меня бирок на
don’t have tags for it  on a package, this kind of bread costs
него нет на пакете вот такой хлеб стоит
45 rubles, a brick of white flour from the highest
45 руб кирпичик с белой муки с высшего
grade, here
сорта вот
it is. Well, I read, look, there are no such prices,
он Ну вот я читаю смотри нету таких цен
even like this at the enterprises
даже так вот на пред вот на предприятиях
wholesale trade and rye bread 77 rubles
оптовой торговли да хлеб ржаной 77 руб
Wheat bread 993
хлеб Пшеничный 993
rubles Well, it can’t be, I’m
руб Ну это не может быть я же тебе
telling you, I live here, I’m just doing it Well,
говорю я же тут живу я это просто Ну вот
I don’t know how you
так я же не знаю как у вас там что-ты
do things there, what kind of prices do you have there
там набираешь что у вас за цены там
horse So this is what you have, I
такие конские Так это у вас это же я
see I’m telling you, maybe a
смотрю Я же тебе говорю может бы а Ско
How much is the weight, how much is the weight of your
сколько вес сколько вес твоего
bread Well, 800 g, in my opinion, a bun, in my opinion,
хлеба Ну 800 г по-моему булка по-моему
800 GS, this thing  800 g Are you
800 ГС вот эта штука 800 г Ты что
kidding me Well, or 700 Well, an ordinary
прикалываешься Ну или 700 Ну обычная
ordinary brick Where do I know that from?
обычный кирпичик Откуда это откуда я
Well, let’s see now, the price of
знаю так Ну сейчас посмотрим так цена
brick bread Yes
хлеб кирпич Да
now Well,
сейчас Ну
yes
да
Interesting 380 380 g Brick bread 380 g
Интересно 380 380 г хлеб кирпичик 380 г
in Krasnodar they write Well, how much does it
в Краснодаре пишут Ну сколько
cost, or 380
стоит так не то 380
g Well, a brick  bread brick 58 rubles
г Ну кирпичик хлеб кирпичик 58 руб вот
this one 380 g this brick It’s light,
этот 380 г вот этот кирпич Он же лёгкий
it’s fluffy you have Well, yes, a brick
он же пушистый у тебя Ну да кирпичик Да
Yes, and even then not even  I don’t know where these
ну и то не даже Даже я не знаю где такие
prices are, we have a maximum of 45 Well, aspic
цены у нас ну максимум 45 Ну то заливной
is
самы
expensive in this bread, in this bread there is
дорого в этом хлебе в этом хлебе там
more air, it weighs 380 g.
больше воздуха он 380 г у тебя
Well, how much does Nuka weigh, here is a
весит Ну а вас сколько весит нука вот
normal loaf. In short, we have your
буханка нормальная Короче у нас ваши
money Yes, ours is normal, normal  a
деньги Да у нас нормальна нормальная
loaf of bread costs Yes, 50 rubles per
буханка хлеба стоит Да 50 руб
kilogram Well, I’m telling you We also
килограммовая Ну я же говорю У нас также
Well, obviously you don’t have this
Ну явно у вас не у вас вот эта фигня
little [ __ ], short damn fluffy, it costs
маленькая короче блин пушистая стоит
that much Why a small big big
столько Почему маленькая большая большой
brick of course not  the little one showed
кирпичик конечно не маленький показал
me how to break it in half Well, so
вот мош её напополам разломать Ну чтобы
I can see what’s in the middle Well,
я посмотрел что в середине Ну
give birth to those that I’m fine
Родите да те что я теть нормально Там
There seem to be big air bubbles there
там походу большие воздушные эти пузыри
It’s empty, there’s no such thing Well, you need to break it,
Он пустой нету такого Ну ну надо ломить
show me I eat it every day, I’m
покажи я его ем каждый день я тебе
telling you that I’ll break it  I work at a
говорю что сес буду ломать Я работаю на
bakery plant. I understand that you have it.
заводе хлебобулочной Я понимаю у тебя он
They add fluff and you have it there
Они добавляют распушил и у тебя там ты
now, when it breaks, you eat there,
сейчас когда его разлома ешь там вот
and that’s the diameter there will be these
таки вот такого диаметра будут эти
bubbles in it.  no it’s not there you you
пузыри в нём нет этого нет там ты ты его
can’t do it you can’t spread butter on it
не сможешь ты на него масло не сможешь
because there’s a hole there no no it’s
намазать потому что там дырки нет нет
easy here mo spread it show show
тут спокойно мо намазать покажи покажи
for the sake of interest Show me the leb kras I’m
ради интереса Покажи мне леб крас я тебе
telling you that I’m now going to break it for a loaf of bread
говорю что я сейчас за болки хлеба буду
This is to undermine it
Вот это подрыва его ломать этот хлеб
show you the bread you went stood up
тебе показать ты ты ж ходил вставал
showed what is normal yes show me
показывал то что нормально да покажи я
the holes I want to see the bubbles
дырки хочу пузыри
I have 18 years of practice Yes in
посмотреть у меня 18 лет практики Да в
bakery products in two years I
хлебобулочных изделиях через два года
will be 20 I’m not
будет двадцатом не интересно
really interested in you  this is if you have such
действительно у вас это если у вас такой
cheap bread, is it really dense
дешёвый хлеб он действительно плотный
or is it just fluffed up? I don’t believe that
или его просто распушил я не верю что
for such a price there can be such dense
может за такую цену быть такой плотный
bread. Why don’t you believe that in principle
хлеб А что ты не веришь у нас в принципе
in Europe we always have the largest harvest?
в Европе самый большой урожай всегда
Look, the thing is that I work for
Смотри я Дело в том что я работаю на
bakery factory Yes, I understand that there
хлебобулочного заводе Да я понимаю что
can’t be such a price for normal
не может быть такая цена за нормальный
bread. Well, it can’t be like that in Ukraine, it
хлеб Ну не может быть полюбому Украине
works here, so I look in Europe,
работает у нас так я смотри я и в Европе
and when we worked with Russia, they also
и вот когда мы с Россией работали тоже
sent it to us  Kharkov
типа отправляли у нас в Харьковской
region, yes it was, well, you have it, there is
области да был ну тебя есть се Хлеб есть
bread, I have bread, yes, like, yes, so what, let’s
Хлеб у меня да типа да ну и что давай
break it together, here I am in the office, now I’m at
разлома тут я на офисе сейчас я на
where I have bread at home in the office, of
откуда у меня на офисе хлеб дома конечно
course, no, are you kidding me or something? Yes, I’m
есть Не ну ты прикалываешься что ли Да
not kidding, I’m telling you  Look, we
не прикалываюсь Я тебе говорю смотри мы
have a stag in Kharkov. I’m telling you,
у нас в Харькове в рогача Я тебе говорю
we have bread without such
у мес хлеб без таких
smoke. We also supplied our own bread to Belgorod.
дымы Мы в Белгород поставляли хлеб свой
Why? Because in Belgorod Yes,
ещё Да почему Потому что в Белгороде Да
it was fluffy
он был с
that’s why you have ours Well, it can’t be for the
наш у тебя поэтому Ну не может быть за
price you say 45 because it’s
такую цену как говори 45 потому что это
more expensive than just the
дороже чем просто сама
flour itself I’m telling you we have
мука Я же тебе говорю у нас заливной
jellied bread. You know what
Хлеб заливной знаешь же такое что такое
jellied bread is. Well, what is jellied bread?
заливной хлеб Ну что такое заливной хлеб
Well, when you pour it into a form like  and he
Ну когда заливают его в форму типа и он
stands
выстаивать
everything Well, come on bread baker Let's continue
всё Ну давай хлебо пекарь Давай дальше
to read what jellied bread is Yes,
почитать что такое заливной хлеб Да
show me
покажи
the Bread So dagda from some damn
Хлеб Так дагда из какого-то блин
feed grain I
фуражного зерна
make with this bread they
делаю с этим хлебом они
Oh hello hello Oh you  what from America? Yes, the
О привет привет О ты что с Америки Да
state of California And where are you from? I’m from Moscow
штат Калифорния А ты откуда Я с Москвы
Well, I’m originally from Rostov, in general I’ve just
Ну я сам родом из Ростова вообще просто
been living for 18 years in California, in 2 years you
живу 18 лет в Калифорнии через 2 года
’ll be twentieth you’re in Moscow Where
будет двадцатой ты в Москву Откуда
I came from, not where I was born here, well, I
приехал я не откуда я родился здесь ну я
see you’re renting a hut somewhere  This is not
смотрю ты снимаешь где-то хату Это не
yours Well, this is a rented apartment Yes, but I
твоя Ну это съёмная квартира Да но я
was born in Moscow A You rent an apartment, you didn’t
родился в Москве А Снимаешь квартиру не
earn money for your apartment from
заработал на свою квартиру сво ть от
Parents renting an apartment, how old are you
Родите снима квартиру сколько тебе лет
20 I mean, in short, you live in  mortgage Yes,
20 Поня короче живёшь в ипотеке Да
why not? I rent an apartment and you
почему нет Я снимаю квартиру а ты уже
can’t even afford a mortgage anymore, I
даже ипотеку не можешь себе позволить
understand. Well, I mean, Prim, wait, wait,
понял Ну в смысле Прим подожди стой А с
where did you get the idea that I need a mortgage and
чего ты взял то что мне нужна ипотека и
I can’t afford it, well, just
я не могу её позволить себе ну просто
in short, how much interest do you have on the
короче сколько у вас сейчас процент на
mortgage now?  242 plus or minus percent
ипотеку 242 плюс-минус процен
Yes, we have 2% in America, how are you even
Да у нас 2% в Америке как вы вообще
paying for such a mortgage? Well, it’s like, well, people have
плачете Ну это в смысле как Ну люди есть
family mortgages, people are building families,
семейная ипотека люди строят семьи
the state is making sure that people
государство идёт на то чтобы люди
start families  they expanded society But this is
создали семьи расширяли общество Но это
what I don’t understand. Wait, you have 2%, but
к чему я не понял Подожди у тебя 2% но у
your cost of housing in your America,
тебя стоимость на жильё в твоей Америке
plus or minus, is the same in your
плюс-минус такой же у тебя в твоей
country, what are you laughing at? Your country is
стране что ты смеёшься у тебя страна
completely credit-worthy. Wait, today the ruble
полностью Подожди у тебя сегодня рубль
has already become a dollar 115  rub and you
уже доллар стал 115 руб а ты мне
will tell me I have a
расскажешь У меня страна
credit country Dude, I lived in Rostov I know
кредитная Чувак я жил в Ростове я знаю у
I have something to
меня есть с чем
compare with okay okay wait a dollar but
сравнить хорошо ладно подожди доллар но
okay wait wait you say wait
хорошо стой подожди ты говоришь стой
wait  wait, you say the dollar is 115, but in
стой стой ты говоришь доллар 115 но в
Russia no one uses the
России никто не пользуется
dollar, look. Why, I’ll explain, if they
долларом смотри Почему объясню если у
import an iPhone from you in Russia,
вас в России завозят iPhone его за
they buy it abroad. In what
границей покупают В какой
currency, not in rubles, in yuan, even in yuan,
валюте не в рублях в юанях даже в юанях
look if you fall, you fall against the dollar
смотри если падаете Вы к доллару падаете
and against the
и к
yuan, because everything  they have an
юанях потому что все они у них же есть
exchange rate with the dollar, the yuan in relation to everything is
курс с долларом юань по отношению всё
tied to the dollar, yes, that is, look, it
привязано к доллару да то есть смотри
turns out If your ruble falls in
получается Если э у вас рубль падает по
relation to  dollar, then in rubles it turns
отношению к доллару то у вас в рублях
out to be more expensive for you True Well,
дороже получается Правда
yes No why plus or minus also
Ну да Нет почему плюс-минус также
comes out Well, the estimate is small Let’s
выходит ну оценка небольшая Давай ещё
look again if, for example, an iPhone costs
раз смотри если например iPhone стоит
1000 dollars like this When the dollar was 70
1000 долларов так Когда доллар был 70
it was one price When the dollar was 115 It’s
это была одна цена Когда доллар 115 Это
already like one and a half  times
уже как бы получается в полтора раза
more by exactly
больше ровно на
50%
50%
Well, well, it turns out you can buy less for
Ну ну так получается можете купить за
your salary,
свою зарплату
so it probably turns out that
меньше так получается наверно то то что
we don’t buy in dollars, we don’t
мы покупаем не в долларах у нас нет
purchase in
закупки по
dollars See E What does it have to do with it  is it you who don’t
доллару Смотри Е Причём тут это ты не
understand or what are you you will you want to
понимаешь или что ты ты будешь ты хочешь
explain to me what we buy in
мне объяснить то то что мы покупаем в
yuan and they buy it for a dollar and
юанях а они покупают это за доллар и у
it costs more in yuan,
них в юанях это стоит
I explain if the ruble falls and
дороже я объясняю если рубль падает да
what is brought from abroad in rubles
то то что привозят изза границы в рублях
becomes more expensive  from you
стаёт дороже у вас
that you buy foreign
что вы покупаете заграничное
cars phones computers there clothes
машины телефоны компьютеры там шмотки
they all cost more in
они все стоют дороже в
rubles
рублях
Why Let me explain again look if
Почему Давай объясню ещё раз смотри если
I’m a businessman bought a phone for 100  before for
я бизнесмен купил телефон за 100 до за
Let's say for uh this 1 dollar
Давай например за э этот 1 доллар вот
I buy something for O dollar in America So
покупаю что-то за О доллар в Америке Так
I sell it here before it cost 70 rubles
и продаю тут раньше это стоило 70 руб
for me and I sold it for 80 now it's
для меня и я продавал за 80 теперь это
120 rubles and I have to sell it for 130
120 руб и я его должен продавать за 130
really that means  you will buy
правда да то значит ты будешь покупать
not for 70 rubles, but for 100, not for 80, but for 130,
не за 70 руб а за 100 не за 80 А за 130
yes, but Well, maybe I don’t understand, but
так да но Ну я возможно не понимаю но у
we don’t have purchases in dollars, we,
нас же нет закупки по доллару у нас же
well, no  we cooperate strange, we have
мы Ну не сотрудничаем странным у нас же
sanctions Well, you imposed, we don’t have
санкции Ну вы наложили у нас же нет
purchases in dollars How good Explain to
закупки по доллару Как хорошо Объясни
me, I’m just a professor of economics at
мне вот я просто профессор экономики в
Somen University Explain to me how I’m in
университете сомен Объясни мне как я
school I just finished 11th grade
школу Я за 11 классов только закончил
Recently, how do you get an
Недавно как вам попадает
iPhone
iPhone
iPhone we bring from China or from
iPhone привозим с Китая либо с
Kazakhstan is correct Well, either from the
Казахстана правильно Ну либо с
United Arab Emirates you
Объединённых Арабских Эмиратов вы
are not buying in rubles, true Yes, so
покупаете не в рублях правда Да так то
if the ruble falls no in rubles either in
если рубль падает нет в руб либо в
rubles or for the currency of the country that
рублях либо за валюту Той страны которую
we take
мы берём
[music]
[музыка]
means look in rubles You definitely don’t
значит смотри в рублях Вы точно не
buy anything abroad, this is
покупаете за границами ничего это
clear because rubles are
однозначно потому что рубли за границе
not quoted abroad. Yes, if you, if your
не котируются Да если ты если у вас
ruble is falling in relation to the dollar and the
рубль падает пок отношению к доллару а
yuan is not falling in relation to the dollar,
юань по отношению к доллару не падает
then the ruble is falling in relation to
значит рубль падает и по отношению к
yuan
юаню
True, repeat again, look at the yuan and the
Правда ещё раз повтор смотри юань и
dollar, the ratio does not change, the yuan
доллар соотношение не меняется курс юаня
to dollar exchange rate and Well, the ruble to the dollar is falling, which
к доллару а Ну рубль к доллару падает то
means the ruble to the yuan too
значит рубль к юаню тоже
is falling Well, yes, in theory, yes it should, that
падает Ну да по идее да должен так то
means it turns out If you
значит получается Если вы за юани
bought the phone for yuan, now it turns out
покупали телефон то теперь получается
it will be more expensive in rubles
это в рублях дороже
Well, depending on which way it falls Well,
будет Ну смотря в какую сторону упадёт
yes, that means it turns out yes What do you
да то значит получается да Что ты мне
want to prove to me that Russia America is
хочешь доказать то что Россия Америка
the top or what?  the essence of the conversation is that
топ или что чему суть разговора так
America is top Look, you started yes What do we have
Америка топ Смотри ты начал да Что у нас
loans there dude Your economy is
там кредиты чувак У тебя экономика
just crashing and you say that America is
просто влетает а ты говоришь что Америка
closed well Russia’s economy is
закре нет хорошо Россию экономико
flying in look Let’s say I’m a simple
влетает смотри Давай так я простой
university professor Yes, I have a
профессор университета Да у меня
small salary  by the standards of California,
небольшая зарплата по меркам Калифорнии
9000 dollars is in Russian back when the
9000 долларов это по-русски ещё когда
dollar was 100 a week ago it
было доллар по 100 неделю назад легче
was easier to count it was 900,000 rubles now
было считать это было 900000 руб теперь
it works out Plus minimum
это получается Плюс минимум
e throw a hundred in short lam it turns out
е накинь соточку короче лям получается
according to you Miln
это по вашему Милн
rubles What do you think is there Tell me
руб Как ты считаешь что там Расскажи мне
now about
теперь про
[music  ]
[музыка]
lending is the biggest year So
кредитованию самый большой годок Значит
it owes someone what kind of country is
она кому-то должна что что за страна
America owed this is not how it
такая которой должна Америка это не так
works but how Well
работает а как Ну
look Wait wait  wait, you
смотри Подожди стой подожди ты
said Wait, you said that America is
сказал Подожди ты сказал то что Америка
top one in terms of national debt or you said
топ один по госдолгу или по ты ты сказал
Yes, what do you have a national debt like So I asked like that
Да что у вас госдолг типа Так я спросил
Who does
так так Кому должна
America owe me
Америка мне
Not well who what countries that China So
Не ну кому каким странам что Китаю Так
stop but Japan has no
стоп а у Японии Нет
national debt Yes has  China has Godot,
госдолга Есть есть у Китая есть Годо
every country has
есть у каждой страны
it. Well, what is
так Ну а что такое
national debt? National debt is the same as debt with
госдолг госдолг - это обще с дол с
other countries. That is, if it
другим странам То есть если
turns out that America owes something to China,
получается Америка что-то должна Китаю
China owes something to America. Yes, both have
Китай что-то должен Америке Да у обоих
national debt, but it’s really
госдолг правда
not like that  once and how well then well So yes So
не так раз а как ну то ж Так да Так А в
What’s
чём
the problem Well that’s Well okay okay
проблема Ну в том Ну ладно окей
you give half the population loans what
кредитовать у тебя половина населения то
lives on a credit card What is it
что живёт в кредитной карты Что это у
you have half the population lives on
тебя у тебя половина населения живёт в
loans Look in Russia look at the
кредитах Посмотри в России посмотри
official data of
официальные данные
Russia now now  even like for their own
России сейча сейчас даже типа на сво
lure Yes, what is wrong with writing off loans in
заманию Да что списывают кредиты в
America? In America, people live
Америке не так в Америке люди живут
normally. Look, they take out
Нормально У нас смотри у нас берут
loans from us for something long-term. Yes, for example,
кредиты что-то долгосрочное Да например
there for a mortgage on this house Yes  but we
там на ипотеку на этот дом Да но у нас
don’t take credit on the phone; it’s only in
не берут на телефон Кредит это только в
Russia that there is such a thing on the
России есть такая штука на
phone. Okay, a credit purchase with a
телефон Ладно кредитная покупка с
credit card is considered taking out a
кредитной карто считается взятием
loan. What is a credit card? You
кредита Что такое кредитная карта Ты
know, yes What? Well, this is money lent by the
знаешь да Что Ну это деньги одолженное
bank for any purchases. The question is
банком на какие-либо покупки вопрос
where does the money come from on a credit card?
откуда деньги попадают на кредитную
Ameri
амери
Man’s card again And how the man returned
Человека ещё раз А как человек возвращал
it Look, if I came to the supermarket and
Вот смотри если я пришёл в супермаркет
paid with a credit card Yes, I
рассчитался кредитной карточкой Да я
paid with someone’s
рассчитался чьими
money with my own, what’s the
деньгами своими своими то в чём
problem, well, nothing, yes What’s the credit here?
проблема ну ни в чём да В чём тут кредит
you don’t you don’t you don’t understand the point at all you’re
ты не ты не ты не понял вообще суть ты
blurting out to me about and no Tell
мне затирает про и нет Расскажи расскажи
me tell me about Credit you also have a credit
мне про Креди вот у тебя тоже кредитная
card All these cards you
карточка Вот все вот эти карточки ты
took Look at all these cards Yes there
взял Посмотри у всех этих карток Да там
is your debit part and
есть и твоя дебитовая частина часть и
there is a credit part so  that is, you can,
есть кредитная так то есть ты можешь
for example, have a credit limit, for example,
себе например кредитный лимит например
take 1,000 dollars or 2,000 there,
взять там 1.000 там долларов или 2.000
and you also count with your own
также и у тебя ты рассчитываешь своими
money. But you can, like if adf go
деньгами Но можешь Типа если адф пойти
You know what it is
Ты знаешь что такое
adf didn’t understand Translate understood yes In short, you
адф не понял Переведи понял да Короче ты
can use for example What is the essence of
можешь использовать например В чём суть
these bank cards? You have
карточек этих банковских Вот у тебя есть
your amount there, for example,
твоя сумма там лежит например
3000 dollars Yes, but for example, if you
3000 долларов Да но например если тебе
don’t have enough for something, you need to
на что-то не хватает вот надо срочно
pay urgently But you don’t have it, yes you can
проплатить А у тебя нету да ты можешь
minus 000 dollars like use Yes, a
минус 000 долларов типа использовать Да
loan if you have to return them like
кредит если и ты должен их вернуть типа
within a certain period Well, that’s normal, no
в определённый срок Ну это нормально
one forces you to
тебя же никто не заставляет ими
use them if not, you count on
пользоваться если нет рассчитываешь
your own, what’s the
своими в чём
problem Wait I don’t understand at all We
проблема Подожди Я вообще не понял Мы
started to lose it So  you
это начали потерял Так ты
look at the mortgage Yes, you throw away what
смотри ипотеку Да вот ты кинешь тем что
you have
у тебя
Well, for property to buy a home in
Ну на имущество на покупку жилья в
America Yes and you think Well,
Америке Да и ты считаешь Ну
this is like the pride of the country Well, yes Because
это типа гордость страны Ну да Потому
if you have 20%, then you
что если у тебя 20% да то ты
overpay, in short, just damn it
переплачиваете короче просто блин раз в
10-15 times more  plus or minus Well, at 2% it’s
10-15 побольше плюс-минус Ну а при 2%
not at all
вообще не так
what is the flag for? Why do you need a flag hanging
а что флаг Зачем теб флаг висит потому
because for the flag of my
что за флаг моей страны
hegemonic country, who is the
гегемона кто такой
hegemon? You don’t even know Russian  I
гегемон Ты даже русского языка не знаеш
get it, I don’t know who the hegemon is, I don’t know who
понял я не знаю кто такой гегемон не Кто
is what a hegemon is, what is
такое что такое гегемон что такое
a hegemon, I don’t know, you’ll get naked, then
гегемон Я не знаю получишь нагу потом
tell me why I’ll be there for free. Well, well, what?
скажи зачем я те буду бесплатно Вот ну
No, why, well, we’re on the Internet, it’s all
ну а что Нет зачем ну мы в интернете всё
just a dude, like, either study yourself or give
просто чувак типа либо учись сам либо за
money to you  I’ll teach America capitalism Well,
бабки тебя научу Америка капитализм Ну
how much I’ll throw you off? Let me throw off some money,
сколько тебе скину Давай те скину денег
tell me how much money you’ll throw me off
расскажешь на ты мне скине такие деньги
if I get ten thousand bucks a month,
если я получаю де штук баксов в месяц
what will you throw off to me? I’ll throw off those rubles  200 I’ll throw
что ты мне скинешь я те рублей 200 скину
them off, that’s enough
те хватит
ruble
руб
ruble less than d dollars
руб меньше д долларов
dude is so rich, you want to throw me off
чувак такой богатый хочешь мне скинуть
Why go work, what should I
Зачем иди работай что я тебе должен
throw off to you? I mean, I don’t want to work. I have
скинуть В смысле Я не хочу работать Я
n’t worked for like 2 weeks now,
вот уже как 2 недели не работаю ну супер
well done, don’t work, you know that
молодец не работай ты в курсе то что от
work is a waste  are dying Well, you’re not a
работы кони гибнут Ну ты же не
horse Why
конь Почему
me You still ask why it’s
я Ты ещё если спрашиваешь почему это
twins Let’s do it for you I for
двойне Давай так я мо для тебя я для
myself no no
себя
yes of course
не не да конечно
Hello
Здравствуйте Здраствуйте
Hello Hello me  from Brussels Where are you from And I'm
Здравствуйте я из Брюсселя Вы откуда А я
from Moscow and what do you think Ukraine is worth and I
из Москвы а что у вас Украина стоит а я
installed a VPN, I talked with the Ukrainians before
VPN ставил с украинцами общался перед
this And without wine it doesn't work without wine
этим А без вина не получается без вина у
I then have Brussels and in short they
меня тогда стоит Брюссель и короче
show that Well, they don't choose I
показывают что Ну они не выбирают я
installed Ukraine so that I would get
ставил Украину чтобы попались мне
Ukrainians  who choose Ukraine,
украинцы которые выбирают Украину
you know, I don’t think that Ukrainians
понимаете Я не думаю что украинцы
choose Ukraine, there are a lot of them, but there
выбирают Украину есть есть их очень но
are, yes. Just sometimes I’ll now explain
есть да Просто иногда я сейчас объясню
why Donbass and Lugansk have these
почему у Донбасса и у Луганска у них эти
Ukrainian SIM cards  and they can’t
украинские симки и они не могут
get rid of the Ukrainian badge.
отвязаться от украинского значка Вот от
That’s why I didn’t know, I understood, and in Crimea too, and
этого а не знал понял и и в Крыму тоже и
they say that it’s impossible to talk
они говорят что невозможно поговорить
because the Ukrainians scroll through. But
потому что украинцы пролистывать А с
we can talk to the Russians anyway.
россиянами мы и так можем поговорить Я
I’m from Rostov myself. Look, I’m from
са Я сам родом Смотри Я сам родом из
Rostov myself, but  I’ve been living in Brussels for 18 years,
Ростова но я уже 18 лет живу в Брюсселе
in 2 years there will be twenty so
через 2 года будет двадцатка так
Yes, Rostov is given and you know how
Да Ростов дано причём знаете как
interesting it is When the Ukrainians, I watched
интересно Когда украинцы вот я смотрел
their reaction They  they see that I’m from
ихнюю реакцию Они видят что я с
the European Union right away Oh well done hearts and
Евросоюза сразу Ой молодец сердечки а
then I say that I’m Russian from
потом я говорю что я русский из
Rostov they change their face immediately
Ростова они меняются лицо сразу
claims right away such impudence
претензии сразу такое наглость
turns on right away
включается сразу
I and you’ve been talking for a long time here in the
я а Вы давно разговариваете вот в чат
roulette chat roulette chat 3
рулетки чат рулетки 3
days No just 3 days just 3 days Yes
дня Нет всего 3 дня всего 3 дня Да
just  I would like it to be at least a
просто я хотелось были бы хотя бы
few years I would say that I
несколько лет Я бы сказала бы что я
noticed that they no longer shout Glory to
заметила что они уже не кричат Слава
Ukraine you didn’t notice this Because you
Украине вы не заметили этого Потому что
don’t have time to turn it on earlier  they have already done it
раньше не успеваешь включит они уже по
several times and until you answer them
несколько раз и пока ты не ответишь им
something they don’t calm down on this
чего-нибудь они не успокаиваются на эту
topic, ours already have a whole bunch of jokes about the
тему у наших уже целая куча шуточек по
city of Moscow itself. I told you I
сами ского города Москва Я же сказала
understood simply. How is life in
Понял просто А как там сейчас жизнь в
Russia now, okay listen I’m retired now,
России нормально слушайте Я сейчас на
that’s it  What we lacked in the
пенсии всё Чего нам не хватало в
Soviet Union now I have I have a
Советском Союзе сейчас есть у меня У
hundred
меня сто
diel my
диель меня
classmate naya bandar in this in Rostov
однокласница ная бандар в этом в Ростове
we were sitting at a desk a
была мы с ней за партой сидели
pretty girl like that you know
симпатичная такая девочка была знаете
how this is school love and so  further Yes
как это школьная любовь и так дальше Да
and she I say Nastya Come to me in
и она Я говорю Настя Поехали ко мне в
Brussels She says well damn here How to
Брюссель Она говорит ну блин тут Как
leave now there is no because she says there is
выехать сейчас нет пото что говорит
no work in Russia yes she says the salary is
работы нет в России да говорит зарплата
small in Rostov there is no work I have
маленькая в Ростове работы нет меня там
relatives living there you
родня жит вы
say specialties Maybe she is
говорите специальности Может она
some kind and she  an
какой-нибудь а она преподаватель
English teacher and there is no work, but he
английского языка и работы нету да
says that somehow the hatred of the
говорит что как-то Ненависть к
English language has started and in short, people don’t
английскому языку пошла и короче не
want to send their children to learn
хотят люди отдавать детей учить
English, listen, my
английский слушайте у меня у моей
door sister’s son lived in Holland for a very
дверной сестры сын в Голландии очень
long time  he worked at Google, he’s
долго жил он в Гугле работал он
a computer scientist, he’s back, he’s back. Well,
компьютерщик вот вернулся вернулся Ну
really, we’re already afraid to ask him whether
правда мы уже боимся его спрашивать
he’ll go back or not, he lived there for about
поедет он обратно или нет он там где-то
five years, but look, he’s
лет пять прожил но смотри машину
buying a car. I asked him. He says, Well, I don’t
покупает Я его спросила Он говорит Ну не
know, well, there’s housing here, there’s work, there’s work,
знаю ну здесь вот жильё есть работа есть
you can do it remotely.  to work a car I bought my
можно удалённо работать машину я купил
mother lives nearby What else is needed Well, we
мама рядом живёт Что ещё надо Ну и так
don’t put so much pressure, of course I would like to be
так не давим конечно хотелось бы чтобы
with my mother, yes Well, it turns out that the
вот с мамой рядом был да Ну получается
salary says Yes, that she works at a
зарплаты говорит Да что она работает в
school, teaches English,
школе преподаёт английский зарплата
her salary is 45,000 rubles  listen, with the English
45.000 руб у неё слушайте с английским
language, she can earn a lot of money,
языком она может бешеные деньги
full of tutoring work,
зарабатывать полно репетиторский работы
so you have to work, but as if she
так работать надо да как если она
graduated from university, she works at a school
заканчивала университет работает в школе
in a state that produces oil, gas,
в государстве которая добывает нефть газ
diamonds and only gets 45,000 rubles like
алмазы а 45.000 руб только получает как
that. And how much does she pay for utilities,
такое А сколько она платит за коммуналку
you didn’t ask How much she has  there is no
вы не спросили Сколько у неё остаётся
living money left, there is nothing left. Well,
живых денег ничего не остаётся Ну
listen, this is not commensurate. I have
слушайте Это не соизмерима у меня
a niece, she is also a teacher, only she
племянница она тоже педагог только она
works with sick children, I
занимается с больными детьми
understand, yes, correctional Well, she
вот Поня поняли да коррекционный Ну она
works for her  there are about four children there,
работает у неё там где-то четыре ребёнка
her work comes to them, she has enough
она работа приезжает к ним ей хватает
money She earns very decent money,
денег Она очень прилично зарабатывает
she can take more, she can
она может больше взять она может меньше
take fewer children She works 4 days a week
детей взять Она работает 4 дня в неделю
teachers They can spin as they please Let him
преподаватели Они же могут как угодно
take tutoring,
крутиться Пусть репетиторство берёт
let him go to a private school
пусть пусть идёт в частную школу
to work  what about Wait, what about
работать каки как Подождите а что
teachers who in public schools
учителя которые в государственных школах
have to live on the Internet? Why on the Internet? Let them
должны в нете жить Почему в нете Пусть
also listen to the teachers at school, you yourself
Ещё слушайте учителя в школе это вы сами
imagine working at school, my husband
представляете работу в школе у меня муж
was a teacher there, you can take as
был преподаватель там ты можешь сколько
many lessons as you want or at all
угодно уроков набрать или вообще
You can  work 2 hours a
набирать Ты можешь работать 2 часа в
week Or you can work every day, she
неделю А можешь работать каждый день она
says that now go to the store
говорит что сейчас вот В магазин зайти
and just buy some cottage cheese for
да творожок просто творожок какой-то
200 rubles as soon as
купить 200 руб как
it goes out, listen, my pension is 35,000
вылетит слушайте у меня пенсия 35.000
so me, well, really, I still have a deposit
так меня ну правда у меня ещё есть вклад
from which I receive interest, but
с которого я получаю проценты но тем не
nevertheless, with this 35,000 I pay for an apartment.
менее у меня с этих 35000 за квартиру я
I have a large apartment
плачу У меня большая квартира со всеми
with everyone, with Internet and light, I
со всеми с интернетом со светом там я
pay somewhere there  6500 out of
плачу где-то 6500 из
35 And that also remains Well, roughly
35 И чего и тоже остаётся Ну и грубо
speaking, per week Well, roughly speaking, I
говоря в неделю Ну грубо говоря в я
usually order groceries Well, so as
обычно заказываю продукты Ну чтобы
not to carry heavy loads Well, about 3-4 piss,
тяжести не таскать Ну где-то 3-4 сся ну
well, look, she tells me, she
это вы ну смотрите она мне говорит она
called me Well, we contacted by
звонила мне Ну мы связывались по
video call on WhatsApp and she calls,
видеосвязи по Ватсапу и она звонит
cries,
плачет
says Andrey,
говорит Андрей
I work as an English teacher at
Я работаю преподавателем английского в
school, yes, 45,000
школе да 45.000
rubles is not enough for the children, there is not enough for
руб не хватает на детей не хватает на
myself to go to a movie, says in the
себя кино чтобы сходить говорит вот в
Soviet Union, her mother could  go to the cinema
Советском Союзе её мама могла в кино
Yes, the state gave the children with
сходить Да детей государство выдал с
mom how many hours mom mother
мама сколько мама часов мама тоже
was also a teacher mom was a teacher in the Soviet Union
педагог была мама в Советском Союзе была
Yes how many hours mom drank
педагог Да сколько мама часов пила
Ask how much Less less Yes she
Спросите скоко Меньше меньше Да она
now works at one and a half times the rate
сейчас работает на полторы ставки
Well, teachers always worked at one and a half
Ну и всегда преподаватели на полторы
rates they work well because
ставки работали они работают ну потому
that they work until 2 o’clock and then
что они до 2 часов работают а потом ещ
usually there is management like this cool
обычно руководство как это классное
management or some kind of clubs were held.
руководство или какие-то кружки вели
Therefore, there was always one and a half hours. If you
Поэтому всегда полторы были Если ты
want women usually whose husbands,
хочешь женщины обычно у которых мужья
let’s say, earned good money, they
допустим хорошо зарабатывали они
generally worked part-time
работали вообще на полставки по 2-3 часа
They worked there for 2-3 hours during the week so that they could get
там в течение недели отрабатывали чтобы
experience, teachers can earn
стаж шл преподаватели могут зарабатывать
very
очень
good money, they remembered with her
хоро ста с ней вспоминали
with Nastya, they remembered our another
с Настей вспоминали нашего ещё одного
classmate Sanya Prokhorov, yeah, there was also a
одноклассника Саню Прохорова Угу тоже
guy who was an excellent student, he was a gold medalist, he didn’t
парень отличник был золотой медалист не
find
нашёл
a job, three children went on a contract
работу трое детей пошёл на контракт
to earn
чтобы заработать
money, he died
деньги погиб в
passed in Ukraine last
Украине прошло в прошлом
month, can we have a minute of silence for
месяце можно можно минуту молчания за
the sleigh?
сани прохо
Sorry, I’m just a war - This is also
Извините я просто война - Это тоже
work. It’s clear, you know everything, he
работа Понятно всё знаете он
was from the first grade, the three of us were friends,
был мы с первого класса мы трое дружили
I’m Nastya Bondarchuk and  Sanya
я Настя Бондарчук и Саня
Prokhorov I remember
Прохоров помню
when we began the period of primary
когда у нас начался период первичного
puberty, we
созревания полового мы
started flirting with Nastya. Yes, and we
начали заигрывать к Насте Да и мы
fought with Anya. I gave him
побились с Ане Я ему тогда
different things out of
Разно из
jealousy. Cockerels and such hens. Yes, he was
ревности Петушки да такие курочки Да он
offended by me, and now when he went, he
обиделся и вот сейчас когда он пошёл он
was a medalist, he was very correct.  he
медалист был он очень правильный был он
won’t offend anyone in a child’s life,
в жизни ребёнка не обидит
and how did it happen that such a
и как так получилось что такой человек
bright person, he’s not like a gold medal, he’s a
светлый он не то что золотая медаль это
golden head, he was just
золотая голова у него была просто
golden, he was doing math, so I was sitting there solving
золотая он математику вот я сидел решал
He did the test for the whole lesson in 10 minutes
контрольную целый урок он так 10 минут у
and
сделал и
he didn’t have money to provide for his
он не имел денег чтобы обеспечить своих
three children, he went to
трёх детей пошёл на
his job. Why didn’t he find a job with
сво работу Почему о работу не нашл с
such abilities? Well, why does anyone
такими способностями Ну а почему кому он
need him? He was a university teacher and
нужен он в университете преподаватель
says 57,000 rubles. Andryukha says
был говорит 57.000 руб Андрюха говорит
listen.  Well, I beg you, Well, this is something, this is
послушайте Ну я вас умоляю Ну это что-то
something they’re not telling you, or
это что-то такое вам не договаривают или
again, I have a husband, my niece, he
у меня опять же муж моя племянница он
teaches at three universities, he’s
преподаёт в трёх университетах он
actually a very famous physicist, he’s at the
вообще-то очень известный физик он в
institute  he teaches atom at Moscow State University and also in
институте атома в МГУ преподаёт и ещё в
this, how is it Fryazina, there is an institute. He
это как это фрязина там институт Он у
gets about
него получается в месяц где-то порядка
120,000 a month, so for three universities, it’s
120.000 так вот за три университета
correct to pay him extra for three
правильно ему доплат три
universities. Well, that’s why it
университета Ну ну поэтому и 12
turns out to strip 12 by Wait, he’s not
получается раздеть по Подождите Он же
there not not in  everyone works for 8 hours,
там не не не в каждом по 8 часов
he wanders back and forth.
работает он туда-сюда мотается Ну так
Well, look, it turns out that not every
вот смотрите да получается не каждого
teacher will be hired like that at different
преподавателя возьмут так в разные
universities. Where is he, uh, he’s with us, yes,
университеты Куда Вот он ээ он у нас да
he’s a mathematician  talented mathematician all
он математик талантливый математик всё
here in Rostov Come on 57,000 rubles he
вот в Ростове Давай 57.000 руб он
says and
говорит и
that at the neighboring university the department of
что в соседнем университете тоже кафедра
mathematics is also occupied and that’s it and go and
математики занято и всё и говори и пошёл
go talk in college anywhere you can
пошёл говори в колледже где угодно можно
teach burn his wife Lily says Go,
преподать гори жена его Лили говорит Иди
in short, give up your mathematics or
короче кидай свою математику ти и Или
go to s  if you earn money there they immediately gave
иди на с заработаешь там сразу давали
them a million then and even 200,000 a month
Там миллион тогда да и 200.000 в месяц
Yes, he went and got a million
Да он пошёл миллион
literally as long as he
получил буквально сколько он был
lasted  3 weeks, that is, he didn’t even
продержался 3 недели то есть он даже не
receive payment for the transfer of some military
получил выплату за пер какая-то военная
specialty No, they
специальность Нет там на контракт
recruited everyone for a contract What military
набирали всех Какая военная
specialty? He’s a little thin Well, as
специальность Он худой немножко Ну как
you know, as usual, those who recruit without
знаете как обычно те кто набирают без
military specialization for another month, what is it
военно специально ещё месяц как это
called, combine training Yes, yes there in
называется соеди обучение Да да там в
he says they put on training, forced them to
учебку он говорит положили заставляли их
clean up the territory there, that’s all the
там убирать территорию вот и всё
training was, and then they brought it to
обучение было а потом привезли под
Donetsk, he says
Донецк он говорит
Andryukha Bakhmut, you know
Андрюха бахмут знаете
Bakhmut, he was among those who
бахмут вот он был среди тех кто
stormed Bakhmut
штурмовал бахмут
this  fate, he
это судьба у он
sent
скидывал
photos, they come in, Bach says, and there
фотографии заходят Бах говорит ан там же
were battles there, such shelling destroyed them here,
бои были такие обстрелы уничтожили тут
Bakh, there is a girl of 8
Бах стоит девочка 8
years old with a boy of 4 years old, brother and sister, they
лет с мальчиком 4 года брат и сестра они
come into the house, they clean up, they do the stitching, where the
заходят дома зачистку делат сшивают где
parents,
родители
the mother, with the mark, was covered with
мать с отм прит был засыпала их
rubble at home for 7 days, this is an eight-year-old  the
обломками дома 7 дней это восьмилетняя
girl was there under shelling with her
девочка была там под обстрелами с
four-year-old brother, they ate the food
четырёхлетним братом они съели еду
and it was disgusting,
и противно
they boiled
это они сварили
the cat and drained it.
кошку и сли
Well, well, they didn’t find it in the whole city. So
Ну хорошо во всём городе не нашли Так
what kind of adult  there everyone was hiding in their houses
какая взрос там все прятались по домам
Everyone was hiding, no one went, I understood
Все прят никто не ходил я поняла
the adults went to fetch water but
взрослые за водой ходили
they didn’t take the children, no one took
ка не прихватили детей никто не взял
the children with them, I don’t know how it happened
детей к себе не знаю как так получилось
Every man for himself or whatever he was and he
Каждый сам за себя или что был и он
says, she says in a trembling voice,
говорит она дрожащими голосом говорит
there’s something to eat  he says I had some
есть что-то покушать он говорит у меня
Snickers so I got her, she
сникерсов так был Я достаю ей она
washes T half for herself half for
размывает Т половину себе половину
her brother Yes, her hand is covered in this chocolate She’s
братику Да рука в этом шоколаде Вот она
even shaking, she eats and eats and he
даже трясётся она ест е съедает и он
says I’m like this  She eats my heart
говорит я вот как меня аж сердце от она
out and asks why you
доедала и спрашивает зачем вы сюда
came here, speaks Russian and he
пришли говорит на русском языке и он
speaks and I understand that we came and
говорит и я понимаю что мы мы пришли
destroyed her parents who spoke
уничтожили е родителе которые говорили
Russian. She speaks Russian; they
на русском языке Она говорит на русском
destroyed her city; in short, in Sana
уничтожили её город короче в Сане было
it was Sanya
он Саня
Prokhorov with  something of tacit consent for
Прохоров с чего-то молчаливого согласия
8 years they were silent in Ukraine 8 years they were
вот 8 лет молчали в Украине 8 лет они
silent you ask any Ukrainian
молчали вы спросите у любого украинца
They say We lived so well So this
Они говорят Мы так хорошо жили Так эта
girl Sanya Prokhorov says Look,
девочка вот Саня Прохоров говорит Смотри
I don’t understand why we  once the girl I Yes,
я не понимаю зачем мы раз девочку Я Да
why didn’t they bomb them because they
зачем Бах их не разбомбили потому что
were sitting there in the city in the city,
там сидели в горо ври льные воны
look Sanya Prokhorova says Yes,
смотрите Саня Прохорова говорит Да
look, if they were even sitting there, let
смотри если там даже сидели за Пусть
people sit and live normally, this
сидели бы люди себе нормально жили эта
girl studied, played, her
девочка училась игралась ходили её
parents went to work, none of them, they talked
родители на работу никто их они говорили
about  Russian language And you are definitely from the
по русскому языку А Вы точно из
Rostov region Slava Ukraine
Ростовской области Слава украи
[laughter]
[смех]
guys it was divine Let's like the
пацаны це было божественно Давайте лайк
comment and leave it
пиписка комент и киньте це
we write on th Telegram directly at once axis
мым пись на й Telegram прямо зараз ось
VN
ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube Zaga
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube Зага
us through the skarg ORV in your ban and even
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
more video I don’t show people immediately I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams For this purpose,
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we need Mali operational link to
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
write directly at once and Popik  there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegra okrim video also tsikava and
телегра окрим видео ще теж е цикава и
korisna information and we will
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava ukraini
YouTube Слава украини
write L
пиши L